Hello English learners, welcome
to English Pod, my name is Marco.
And my name is
Catherine, and today we're
talking about something
very, very important
in the computer age Internet
Internet and Internet connections.
Right, I think well so
many people use the
Internet now and have
it, but it's sometimes
a little bit complicated
to maybe get a plan
or maybe if you're
not too familiar with
the terms, that's where we're
going to be looking at today.
So listen out for some
of these words today,
we're talking on the
phone with someone who's
going to help us get a
plan, let me come back,
we're talking all about what some
of these words and phrases mean.
So if you're confused, just wait a
couple seconds and we'll be back.
Welcome to Gallonit, how can I help you?
Hi, I would like to get an Internet
plan from my house, of course.
We have three different plans with
different prices you can choose from.
The first one is the cheapest, but
most basic plan, which is $30 a month.
This is for broadband Internet,
with a download speed of 512 KBPS.
I have no idea what KBPS means.
I just want to be able to get online,
play games and chat with my friends.
Oh and watch movies online as well.
Well, this connection might
be a bit too slow for your needs.
I suggest you get the
premium package for $50
a month, which includes
a connection speed
of two megabytes.
That way you can play
games online without any lag.
This package also
includes a wireless router
and a personal
firewall, absolutely free.
Do I have to pay an installation fee?
Lucky for you, this month we aren't
charging our normal installation fee.
You're saving yourself
a hundred bucks right
there, and we'll
throw in this pen drive.
Awesome!
Alright, so interesting,
a lot of these technical
terms specifically for Internet and
computers and connection and all that stuff.
Yeah, and the nice thing
about some of these
words is that they can be
used in other ways as well.
So, we're learning about these
and expanding our vocabularies,
but they're useful in
many other contexts as well.
Okay, so let's get started with these
words now in language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
So this first phrase,
for example, is
something that you see
advertised all the time.
And it's, well, it's a kind
of Internet connection.
Broadband Internet.
Okay, so Internet
is pretty clear, but
broadband you might be asking,
what the heck can this mean?
Okay, so you have broad.
So broad means wide.
Wide, and a band is basically kind of
like a frequency at which something works.
Like bandwidth.
Band width, huh?
So you have broad band, you
have fast or high speed Internet.
That means the bigger the space is,
the more information can be transferred.
So it's a fast connection essentially.
Exactly.
More broadband, we had dial up Internet.
Yeah.
Remember AOL?
So it's so slow.
You have to use your modem and call a
number and then get connected by telephone.
So it was a dial up
connection, but it was so slow.
And every time it broke,
the connection would break.
You had to dial up again
and do the whole process.
It's so annoying.
Exactly.
So fortunately, now
not many people use dial
up anymore and we
have broadband Internet.
Now that if you have
broadband Internet, it's
really convenient
because you can download
any type of application
or music, videos, et cetera.
Right.
So this is another key computer word that
actually has a couple of different uses.
For example, as you said, you can
download music or download photos.
That means you find a
photo on the Internet that
you like and you can
save it on your computer.
But you can also have a
download so it can be a thing too.
Okay, so if maybe you're downloading three
different files, you have three downloads.
Okay.
So to download and download, very good.
So now we Internet, you have different
speeds as we talked about, right?
How fast you're downloading something
and the guy mentioned 512 KBPS.
Oh, no, not everyone of these KBPS.
So this man actually,
this is pretty simple.
You can think about kilobytes, you've
heard about megabytes, kilobytes.
This is a size that how fast you can
receive these packets of information.
So 512 kilobytes per second per second
that's, I have no idea how much that is.
It's maybe a lot.
It sounds like a lot.
Right.
Well, basically, it
is a lot, but we saw
later that he was asking for a
connection to speed of two megabytes.
Oh, so mega is bigger than KBPS, right?
Right.
So these are different speeds
of transferring information, right?
So this is a way for you to see
what kind of internet plan you want.
Exactly.
And so you have kilobytes,
we have megabytes.
And basically you want a faster connection
speed because you want to avoid lag.
Ooh, lag, all right.
This is a word that you can use in
a lot of different ways, for example.
My brother always lags
behind, okay, so it's, it's a verb.
But in this case, we're talking
about the noun, so lag is slowness.
Yeah, it's like a delay.
Yeah, it's a delay in something.
So in this case, I can't even play my
video games because there's too much lag.
So that means the internet's
too slow, too slow, exactly.
So that's what happens when you have
a slow connection speed, you have lag.
And as you can say, it refers to
something that's slow or delayed.
So you can use it in
other contexts when you
want to say something
is a little bit slow.
Well, another key thing
here, as we're talking
about internet
connections, is the router.
So router is something that helps
us to route an internet connection.
So for example, so
it basically distributes
the internet connection to different
computers or to different users.
And some of these you plug in,
and some of them are wireless.
That means without a wire.
So a wireless router
is something that little
box in your house that
allows you to maybe
have three or four computers
on one broadband connection.
Right.
So it's very popular now.
You go to Starbucks and you have Wi-Fi in
order to have Wi-Fi or wireless internet.
You need a router, a wireless router.
Okay.
So wireless router.
And finally, what is something that
might get in the way of a connection?
You have a firewall, very important security
measure when navigating the internet.
All right.
So a personal firewall
is a firewall that
you have on your computer to
keep people from spying on you.
This keeps other people out.
Mm-hmm.
So it's exactly that.
It's a wall between your
computer and the outside world.
So it protects you from any
type of maybe malicious intruders.
Right.
And oftentimes governments
and public offices,
things like that law offices, they have
firewalls to protect the information that
they store because it's so
important that it's secretive.
Yeah.
Because there are
many different types of
firewalls, but a personal
firewall is just a basic one.
Great.
So that is our language takeaway for today.
Let's check out this dialogue again
and slow it down a bit this time.
Welcome to Gallonit.
How can I help you?
Hi.
I would like to get an
internet plan from my house.
Of course.
We have three different plans with
different prices you can choose from.
The first one is the cheapest, but
most basic plan, which is $30 a month.
This is for broadband internet,
with a download speed of 512 KBPS.
I have no idea what KBPS means.
I just want to be able to get online,
play games, and chat with my friends.
Oh, and watch movies online as well.
Well, this connection might
be a bit too slow for your needs.
I suggest you get the
premium package for $50
a month, which includes a
connection speed of two megabytes.
That way, you can play
games online without any lag.
This package also
includes a wireless router
and a personal
firewall, absolutely free.
Do I have to pay an installation fee?
Lucky for you, this month we aren't
charging our normal installation fee.
You are saving yourself
a hundred bucks right
there, and we'll
throw in this pen drive.
Awesome.
Alright, great.
So we just heard all of these awards that
we looked at before, but now why don't we
take a look at some of these
phrases in fluency builder?
Fluency builder.
What's this first one?
I can't read it.
I have no idea.
What?
Didn't you write it down?
I have no idea what you're talking about.
Alright.
Enough gain.
No.
I have no idea.
This is, well, it's going to treat
this as a phrase that gets said as is.
We're not going to
take bits and pieces of it.
So I have no idea or he has no idea
as a way to say, listen, I don't know.
I don't know.
I really don't know.
Right.
The guy was talking
about KBPS and all these
things and the other guy was like, I
have no idea what you're talking about.
I don't understand.
And I can definitely, you can relate.
Yeah.
Well, we'll leave that for another one.
But after this, it got a box.
Alright.
So box.
What?
Is this slang?
Bucks.
100 bucks.
200 bucks.
Right.
So box is basically another
way of saying dollars.
Alright.
So this is a way for, well, this is the way
that most Americans talk about money.
It's a one buck is one US dollar.
Alright.
So kind of brought 10 bucks, Marco.
Right.
Oh, yeah.
Sure.
There you go.
Now, you can only use
it for American currency.
Right.
You can't use it for like euros or.
No.
You can't say like 10
euros would be 10 bucks.
No, no, no, no.
Usually you say this about
American dollars and you say this
just when you're hanging out
or how much does this cost?
No, five bucks.
Very good.
So the guy was telling him about
the price of the internet and everything.
And he said if he's going to throw in a
pen drive, right, he's going to throw it.
I'm going to throw it.
I don't know.
He's going to throw
in a pen drive for free.
Oh, sweet.
So throw in means to, to
add or include, so listen, sir.
Here's your large popcorn and I'm going
to throw in a small Diet Coke for free.
Wow.
You've got generous.
No.
So you throw in something,
it's, you include it for free, right?
Exactly.
So this is usually complimentary item.
Great.
I think this word is really
interesting or this phrase.
So why don't we listen to a couple of
other examples using throw in example one?
If you buy two pizzas, we will
throw in another one for free.
All two.
Tell you what.
I'll buy this computer if you throw in a
pair of headphones, deal example three.
The salesman threw in a subscription to
the local newspaper for buying his product.
Isn't that great?
All right.
Great.
So good examples.
I think it's clear now.
The phrase is all these
words related to the internet.
Absolutely.
Oh, right.
So why don't we listen
to this dialogue for the last
time and then we'll come
back and talk a little bit more.
Welcome to Gallonet.
How can I help you?
Hi.
I would like to get an
internet plan for my house.
Of course.
We have three different plans with
different prices you can choose from.
The first one is the cheapest, but
most basic plan, which is $30 a month.
This is for broadband internet,
with a download speed of 512 KBPS.
I have no idea what KBPS means.
I just want to be able to get online,
play games and chat with my friends.
Oh, and watch movies online as well.
Well, this connection might
be a bit too slow for your needs.
I suggest you get the
premium package for $50
a month, which includes
a connection speed
of two megabytes.
That way, you can play
games online without any lag.
This package also
includes a wireless router
and a personal
firewall, absolutely free.
Do I have to pay an installation fee?
Lucky for you, this month we aren't
charging our normal installation fee.
You're saving yourself
a hundred bucks right
there, and we'll
throw in this pen drive.
Awesome.
So, the internet is a
big deal nowadays, and
now you can do so much
on it, not only navigate
websites anymore, but
watch movies, download
applications, photos,
Facebook, all this type
of things now that you
can do on the internet.
You can even do it
from your phone, like
when you're in the
bathroom or on the train.
I mean, it's scary.
We're always connected.
Right.
So, it's interesting.
You're always connected.
You're always online with people, and it's
actually very noticeable when you maybe
live somewhere else before
you used to have to write letters.
I don't think many people will
receive handwritten letters anymore.
Never.
I'm speaking for myself.
I never receive, and I don't write
them either, so I guess I'm guilty of it.
So now people just send emails.
Obviously, it's more
convenient, but maybe
it's a little bit less
significant maybe than
actually going to the
post office or taking
the time to write a letter,
going to the post office and stuff.
Well, I don't know.
There's something nice
about having a physical
thing you can hold on to, but I wonder if
one day we're going to forget how to write.
Yeah.
You know, like, write with a pen.
With a pen and pencil.
Exactly.
We're going to have
these little PDA's and
these little iPhones,
and they're going to just,
they're going to talk, and they're going
to take everything down a note for you.
Well, now it's kind of
happening with the Kindle, right?
Now you can have
books on this electronic
device that lets you read
through them, and you
can carry a hundred
books with you to the beach.
So now you don't
even really need physical
books, you know, which
is good on some level,
because, you know, you're saving
trees and space and all that stuff.
But there's something
physical about reading a book.
You hold it.
You flip the pages.
You know how many pages you have left.
I don't know.
We'll see.
Maybe I'll be a convert one day, but
for now, I'm good with paper books.
All right.
So what do you guys think about
the internet, about the electronic book?
You can also tell us any
problems or confusion
you have with the things
that we talked about today.
Hopefully everything is clear, but if
not, we are here to answer your questions.
We'd like to do so.
Go to our website, englishpot.com.
All right.
We'll see you guys there.
And until next time.
Goodbye, everyone.
Bye.